<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 09:47:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow State Machine: Letter to Tushar</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/workflow_statemachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 09:47:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/workflow_statemachine/</guid>
      <description>I have been think about my workflow a lot of late decided to write my friend Tushar a letter. Here is that letter in full.
Hey Tush,
I hope you are getting some good relaxation in this weekend. It is a rainy day here in Baton Rouge so we are trapped inside. I have been thinking a lot about my work flow since reading that Gelman piece post I forwarded you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are we looking for in a politician?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/politican_ideaology_leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:15:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/politican_ideaology_leadership/</guid>
      <description>We have been taught to support political candidates whose ideology most nearly matches our own. While being ideological aligned with a candidate is important, not enough weight is given to candidates other traits. As an organization grows larger, the success of the organization is determined less by the vision or execution of the leader and more by the leaders ability to listen and empower others. The United States political system is so large and unwieldy that the impact of a president is not felt through their ideology but their ability to successfully run a large organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Playing Games </title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 13:42:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/games/</guid>
      <description>Jenny, my wonderful partner in crime and teammate, had her birthday last month. I got her a Nintendo Switch, with the game Overcooked. Overcooked is a cooking simulation game. You are in a kitchen with other chefs and you have to collaborate to make customers dishes. While simple in concept, Overcooked is quite deep in how it forces you to work together. The levels are set up so that the only way you can succeed is by delegating and working together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you Solve for Biased Data?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/biased_data_hawk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 16:44:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/biased_data_hawk/</guid>
      <description>My friend Hawkins recently sent me the following question:
 How do you work around biased data sets to produce non discriminatory results in ML?
 I ended up writing him a fair amount while I wan on a plane. My response to him is replicated here in full.
Hey Hawk,
Thanks for asking this question. It is a really important one and it is always nice to think about these problems in a fair amount of depth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for the Offseason</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/personal-planning-for-the-offseason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 22:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/personal-planning-for-the-offseason/</guid>
      <description>One of my friends and teammates asked me for some feedback about what he should be working on during the frisbee off-season. I wrote him an email explaining about how I think about getting better in the off-season before sending him some personal feedback. I thought sending this email would help contextualize how I think about getting better and reaching our goals. Some of the information in here, can be applied to really any skill, not just getting better at frisbee.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>