<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 10:52:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fair Algorithm is not sufficient</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/fair_ai_is_not_enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 10:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/fair_ai_is_not_enough/</guid>
      <description>For the past two weeks, I have been working through Me &amp;amp; White Supremacy, Layla Saed&amp;rsquo;s month long interrogation of white supremacy. I am reading the book, journaling each day and then meeting with a group of co-workers weekly to discuss our experience. While journaling, I noticed my tendency to gravitate toward simple solutions. The chapters about tone policing and cultural appropriation were quite challenged. I was looking for specific guidelines about what my behavior should look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Models and the Scientific Method</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/model_building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:18:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/model_building/</guid>
      <description>In the past year there has been a large focus on what is wrong with the fields of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. Coverage has focused on limitations of current deep learning and machine learning systems. Pieces have highlighted the dangers of implementing systems without understanding their implications or who they are going to impact. These pieces have highlighted areas where these fields need to grow. Machine Learning is still a relatively young field that needs to grow and learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professors</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/professors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 07:58:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/professors/</guid>
      <description>This is list of professors who are doing really cool work:
 Cynthia Rudin Andrew Gelman Michael L. Jordan Moritz Hardt Jacob Andreas Rachel Thomas Jeffery Heer Brent Hecht  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>