<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Urban Policy on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/urban-policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Urban Policy on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 17:04:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/urban-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing Like A State</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/seeing_like_a_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 17:04:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/seeing_like_a_state/</guid>
      <description>Seeing Like A State is one of professor James Scott&amp;rsquo;s most well know pieces. It takes a comprehensive look at high modernism and why certain approaches to improve outcomes have failed. The book is centered on understanding what measures have been used to simplify very complex behavior. Through a few in depth case studies the book highlights how this simplified understanding can lead to bad outcomes. It is not that this simplification inherently leads to bad outcomes but when it is combined with the believe that you can do no wrong, it will often lead to those in power hurting others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden Gates: Fighting for Housing in America</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/golden_gates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:52:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/golden_gates/</guid>
      <description>Golden Gates by Conor Daugherty tells a meandering story of housing in the Bay Area. It combines individual stories focused on specific actors with a larger look at housing policy. We hear about community activists, politicians and people being forced from their homes. It combines a larger argument about problems with housing with an in depth looking at how the housing crisis impacts individual people.
Reading The Color of Law by Richard Rothstein gave me a sense of historical patterns and how the housing market has become so inequitable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>