<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policy on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policy on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:49:56 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the Legal Compatibility of Fairness Definitions</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2021/legal_compatability_fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:49:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2021/legal_compatability_fairness/</guid>
      <description>Paper Link
By Alice Xiang: Linkedin, Twitter and Inioluwa Deborah Raji: Linkedin, Twitter
Paper Motivation There has be a lot of literature that demonstrates gaps in machine learning fairness definitions.
Paper Contribution This paper shows that current fairness definitions misunderstand the legal terminology they claim to be derived from. These definitions are inappropriately co-opting legal language. This paper shows examples of this misalignment and explains what we can learn from these differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deconstructing the Filter Bubble: User Decision-Making and Recommender Systems</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/deconstructing_filter_bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:47:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/deconstructing_filter_bubble/</guid>
      <description>By Guy Aridor, Duarte Goncalves, Shan Sikdar
Paper Link
Paper Motivation There is a common theory that recommender systems lead to user consuming more similar content over time. This kind of affect is called a filter bubble where each user or group of users ends up in their own little bubble.
Paper Contribution The paper finds that recommendation can alleviate natural-filter bubble effects, but it also leads to more homogeneity across users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Data Strikes”: Evaluating the Effectiveness of a New Form of Collective Action Against Technology Companies</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/data_strikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:32:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/data_strikes/</guid>
      <description>By Nicholas Vincent, Brent Hecht, Shilad Sen
Paper Link
Paper Motivation There have been some calls for “data strikes“ in response to worries about the power of large technology companies. These strikes aim to starve business plans predicated on collecting large amounts of user data. Little is known about how a data strike would work or if it would even be effective.
Paper Contribution Focusing on recommender systems, the authors simulate data strikes under many conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hardware Lottery</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/hardware_lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:32:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/hardware_lottery/</guid>
      <description>By Sara Hooker
Paper Link
Paper Motivation Through out history we have seen different research ideas win and lose. Why do some win and others lose? Do the superior ideas always win out?
Paper Contribution This paper introduces the term hardware lottery to explain how some research ideas win out because they are best fit to the current state of hardware. It does not win out because the idea is superior to other research directionsThe author uses examples from early computer science research to show how the hardware lottery can delay research progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decolonial AI: Decolonial Theory as Sociotechnical Foresight in Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/decolonial_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 12:45:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/decolonial_ai/</guid>
      <description>By Shakir Mohamed, Marie-Therese Png, and William Isaac
Paper Link
Paper Motivation Artificial Intelligence has the potential to re-shape our society. These changes could be broadly beneficial but aslo have the potential to be dangerous for vulnerable peoples. To understand the impacts of AI we need to think about values and power. It is the responsibility of the AI community to have ethical foresight and involve many different perspectives.
Paper Contribution The paper explores using post-colonial and decolonial theories to understand advances in AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and Power: Archival Appraisal Theory as a Framework for Data Preservation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/archival_theory_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:30:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/archival_theory_data/</guid>
      <description>By Sarita Schoenbeck and Paul Conway
Paper Link
Paper Motivation Data is being collected ubiquitously. Tech companies are “moving fast and breaking“ things rather than thinking carefully about data storage
Paper Contribution The paper calls upon archival theory to understand control, power, subjectivity and emotion in computing practices related to data storage. The authors test their framework with an interview study. They end by sketching the implications of their framework and suggest having data management practices that focus on legacy, life transitions and control</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Fine-grained Flow Forecasting: A Graph Attention Approach for Bike Sharing Systems</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/bike_share_forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 16:02:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/bike_share_forecasting/</guid>
      <description>By Suining He and Kang Shin
Paper Motivation Accurate bike-flow prediction at the station level is important for a bike sharing service&amp;rsquo;s success. Existing methods are not successful at predicting fine-grained bike flow.
Paper Contribution The authors remedy this problem by proposing a spatiotemporal graph attention CNN for station-level flow prediction. Each bike station is a node and bike rides are edges on a graph. Their network captures differing station-to-station correlations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality of Opportunity in Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/equalized_odds_supervised_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 11:23:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/equalized_odds_supervised_learning/</guid>
      <description>Paper Motivation Model builders may want to ensure their model is fair with regard to a protected attribute. (E.g. Wanting to make sure our model is not discriminating against people because of their race). Previous research has shown that quantifying a model&amp;rsquo;s fairness is not straight forward. Even if the protected attribute is not an input to the model it is still possible that the model is discriminatory.
Paper Contribution The authors present a methodology of adjusting a learned predictor to remove discrimination according to their definition of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter and Tear Gas: The Power and Fragility of Networked Protest </title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 16:31:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</guid>
      <description>Twitter and Tear Gas By Zeynep Tufekci is a pointedly insightful read. I had been planning to read it ever since she was interviewed on Stratechery. It felt like a really good time to read this book with the BLM protests going on across the world. Twitter and Tear Gas is part a history of modern protests, part a personal reflection and part a deep dive on the societal impacts of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking the Electorate: How Campaigns Percieve Voters</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hacking_electorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 13:35:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hacking_electorate/</guid>
      <description>Hacking the Electorate By Eitan Hersh is an depth look at what information is accessible to campaigns and how they use that information to interact with voters. Hersh contextualizes his work by highlighting that he is focusing on the perspective of a campaign. A lot of previous research is through the lense perspective of voters. Hersh&amp;rsquo;s main argument is that by looking through the perspective of campaigns we can understand how campaigns perceive voters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are we looking for in a politician?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/politican_ideaology_leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:15:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/politican_ideaology_leadership/</guid>
      <description>We have been taught to support political candidates whose ideology most nearly matches our own. While being ideological aligned with a candidate is important, not enough weight is given to candidates other traits. As an organization grows larger, the success of the organization is determined less by the vision or execution of the leader and more by the leaders ability to listen and empower others. The United States political system is so large and unwieldy that the impact of a president is not felt through their ideology but their ability to successfully run a large organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidents Happen: Exposing Fallacies in Child Protection Abuse Cases and Reuniting Families Through Aggressive Litigation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2019/accidents-happen-exposing-fallacies-in-child-protection-abuse-cases-and-reuniting-families-through-aggressive-litigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2019/accidents-happen-exposing-fallacies-in-child-protection-abuse-cases-and-reuniting-families-through-aggressive-litigation/</guid>
      <description>By Jessica Horan-Block &amp;amp; Elizabeth Tuttle Newman
Summary This paper by two attorneys at Bronx Defenders argues that quick, decisive, and aggressive action can return children to parents after abuse allegations much faster than traditional approaches. The authors outline how minority and low income parents are more frequently accused of abuse. Parents will bring their children to the Emergency Room in response to accidental injuries or strange physical developments. When the parents explanation for how the injury occurred is not deemed sufficient by the physician, they will be accused of abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
