<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:42:48 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Fairness in Machine Learning Systems: What Do Industry Practitioners Need?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/fairness_practitioners_needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:42:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/fairness_practitioners_needs/</guid>
      <description>By Kenneth Holsten, Jennifer Wortman Vaughn, Hal Daume III, Miroslav Dudik and Hanna Wallach
Paper Link
Paper Motivation There has been a recent surge in research developing tools to mitigate harms of machine learning. For these tools to have an impact they must actually meet industry practitioners needs
Paper Contribution The paper outlines commercial teams‘ challenges and needs when developing fairer ML systems. The authors outline where there is disconnect between the current research and what people actually need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Chapters 4, 5 and 6</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_4_5_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:19:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_4_5_6/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to combine my notes from chapters four, five, and six into one post. These chapters are light on new information and heavier on examples and applications. The power of this book is the number of examples it provides. One way to learn is to look at examples and then adopt them for your own use case. This book is perfect for that type of learning.
Chapter 4 Chapter four is centered on the law of large numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:19:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_3/</guid>
      <description>Notes Chapter 3 in Bayesian Method for Hackers is center on Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC). It is possible to use pymc3 and bayesian models without understanding the underlying algorithms. Understanding this algorithms plays a pivotal role though if we want to be serious practitioners. When our model works out perfectly, not knowing the underlying algorithms is fine. But if we are trying to do anything complicated, our first attempt will almost certainly not work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 16:38:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_2/</guid>
      <description>Notes The chapter explains the syntax of pymc3 and how to turn different concepts into pymc3 code. It outlines the difference between a stochastic variable and determinstic variable
 A stochastic variable is random. This means even if all the information about the variable is known, we do not know what its value is. Drawing a value from a distribution is a stochastic variable. A deterministic variable can be determined from its parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow State Machine: Letter to Tushar</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/workflow_statemachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 09:47:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/research/workflow_statemachine/</guid>
      <description>I have been think about my workflow a lot of late decided to write my friend Tushar a letter. Here is that letter in full.
Hey Tush,
I hope you are getting some good relaxation in this weekend. It is a rainy day here in Baton Rouge so we are trapped inside. I have been thinking a lot about my work flow since reading that Gelman piece post I forwarded you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Prologue and Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 18:08:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_1/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Methods for Hackers is an online textbook created by Cam Davidson Pilon. The book focuses on bridging the gap from theory to practice. The author argues that textbooks often focus on theory to the point where they become inaccessible. By focusing on accessability these methods become avaliable to anyone.
Notes The first chapter begins with an outline of how to think in a bayesian frameworks. Bayesian methods are our process of updating beliefs after seeing new evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>