<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 08:40:13 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Economics for Hard Times</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/economics_bad_times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 08:40:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/economics_bad_times/</guid>
      <description>I have read a lot of &amp;ldquo;pop&amp;rdquo; science books and Good Economics for Hard Times is easily the best. Duflo and Banerjee explore very complex topics with nuance. They do an incredible job of conveying where there is uncertainty and what we know more definitively. Duflo and Banerjee both review the existing literature and expand upon potential future directions. Good Economics for Hard Times provides structure for thinking about complex problems like immigration or automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender in the 21st Century: Marianne Bertrand</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/talks/bertrand_gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 16:15:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/talks/bertrand_gender/</guid>
      <description>This was a talk given at the American Economic Association (AEA) conference at the beginning of January 2020 by Marianne Bertrand. I was recommended this talk by Jenny Wang.
Summary Bertrand begins her talk by highlighting that overall gender differences / bias are heading in the right direction. We see an optimistic story when we look at the wrong trends in gender differences. There are more females in the labor force and less of a difference in girls schooling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing Bandits in Matching Markets</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/bandits_matching_markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 14:26:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/bandits_matching_markets/</guid>
      <description>Summary This paper explores matching in two sided markets through the multi armed bandit problem. An example of a two sided market we can model using multi armed bandits is matching workers to employees. There is a pool of workers and a pool of employees. We want to find the optimal matching of employees and workers. Employees have preferences over workers, and workers have preferences over employees. There has been a lot of working that examines how to achieve an optimal matching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lords of the Realm</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 08:48:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</guid>
      <description>Lords of the Realm by John Helyar chronicles the history of baseball through the eyes of the owners. We generally learn about the history of sports through the great players and their influence on the game. This book looks at the owners and how they shaped the game of baseball as it developed. The book is particularly focused on the labor relations between the players and the owners.
This book showed a completely different side of baseball history than I am used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Blend of Machine Learning and Microeconomics</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/talks/odsc/ml_microecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 09:51:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/talks/odsc/ml_microecon/</guid>
      <description>Talk given by Michael I Jordan
What is Machine Learning? The talk started by Professor Jordan defining what Machine Learning is. He said that machine learning is not some new field of research but it is rather the engineering extension of statistics. He calls back to how there was chemistry for a long time before there was chemical engineering. There was physics and electrical theory before there was electrical engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>