<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non-Fiction on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/non-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non-Fiction on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 14:36:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Mortal</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/being_mortal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 14:36:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/being_mortal/</guid>
      <description>I have read Atul Gawande&amp;rsquo;s writing in the New Yorker over the past year was quite impressed. He has a very measured tone and is very persuasive. Being Mortal was the only one of his books available at the library.
The best non-fiction books are those that combine stories with an analytical view. If it is only stories then often times the book is not making a larger point. Just an analytical argument can often miss the human side of a topic and can be a dry read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salt Fat Acid Heat</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/salt_fat_acid_heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 16:11:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/salt_fat_acid_heat/</guid>
      <description>This book was such a good read, I loved learning the fundamentals of cooking. Most other recipe books give you a bunch of recipes but never explain why something tastes good or why flavors go together. I have been drifting towards this approach to cooking for a while now. I was trying not to follow recipes, but instead use recipes as inspiration. It never felt like following a recipe exactly by the book was sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter and Tear Gas: The Power and Fragility of Networked Protest </title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 16:31:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</guid>
      <description>Twitter and Tear Gas By Zeynep Tufekci is a pointedly insightful read. I had been planning to read it ever since she was interviewed on Stratechery. It felt like a really good time to read this book with the BLM protests going on across the world. Twitter and Tear Gas is part a history of modern protests, part a personal reflection and part a deep dive on the societal impacts of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking the Electorate: How Campaigns Percieve Voters</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hacking_electorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 13:35:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hacking_electorate/</guid>
      <description>Hacking the Electorate By Eitan Hersh is an depth look at what information is accessible to campaigns and how they use that information to interact with voters. Hersh contextualizes his work by highlighting that he is focusing on the perspective of a campaign. A lot of previous research is through the lense perspective of voters. Hersh&amp;rsquo;s main argument is that by looking through the perspective of campaigns we can understand how campaigns perceive voters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trick Mirror: Reflections on Self Delusion</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/trick_mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/trick_mirror/</guid>
      <description>Trick Mirror by Jia Tolentino is a series of essays exploring identity and the self in our current era. Tolentino blends personal stories and self reflections with larger dissections of structural systems in our society. I found Tolentino&amp;rsquo;s writing incredibly compelling. She does not prescribe absolutes and allows nuance to shine through. She does not prescribe exact solutions but rather examines structures in our society and how she navigates them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Ahead in the Rain: Notes to A Tribe Called Quest</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/go_in_rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 11:02:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/go_in_rain/</guid>
      <description>Go Ahead in the Rain: Notes to a Tribe Called Quest is a beautiful book. It blends a memoir, with a history of a rap group, with a history of a time period. While the book is ostensibly about the rap group, it actualls talks about so much more than one rap group. Abdurraqib writes a poetic style of prose that conveys so much emotion.
Abdurraqib writes through the lense of his personal experience with the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch and Kill</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/catch_kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:36:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/catch_kill/</guid>
      <description>Reading Catch and Kill by Ronan Farrow was a real eye opener for me. I knew who Harvey Weinstein was but I did not know any of the details. A lot of the events covered in the book happened while I was in college when I did not really follow the news.
My largest takeaway was that while the book might be centered on Harvey Weinstein, it is actually about so much more than any individual man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Will You Measure Your Life?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/cc_ja_how_measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:10:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/cc_ja_how_measure/</guid>
      <description>I was introduced to this book through Stratechery and Exponent. One of the co-hosts of Exponent, James Allworth, is a co-author of this book. While I have been reading Ben Thompson&amp;rsquo;s (the author of Stratechery) writing for a couple years now, I knew a lot less about Allworth and his background. While James is a co-author of this book, the book is written from the perspective of Clayton Christensen. Christensen a professor at Harvard Business School, is best known for his work The Innovator&amp;rsquo;s Dillema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Economics for Hard Times</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/economics_bad_times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 08:40:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/economics_bad_times/</guid>
      <description>I have read a lot of &amp;ldquo;pop&amp;rdquo; science books and Good Economics for Hard Times is easily the best. Duflo and Banerjee explore very complex topics with nuance. They do an incredible job of conveying where there is uncertainty and what we know more definitively. Duflo and Banerjee both review the existing literature and expand upon potential future directions. Good Economics for Hard Times provides structure for thinking about complex problems like immigration or automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braiding Sweet Grass</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/braiding_sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/braiding_sg/</guid>
      <description>Braiding Sweet Grass is a set of short stories about nature from Robin Kimmerer&amp;rsquo;s life. Kimmerer blends a scientific perspective with a perspective from from her heritage as a Native American. While each story is about an individual relationship between humans and nature, she often makes larger points about how human view themselves in the world. Kimmerer questions human&amp;rsquo;s claim of intelligent supremacy, challenges some of our economic systems and laments different ways our society is narrow minded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Learning</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/a_of_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 08:00:18 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/a_of_learning/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Learning by Josh Waitzkin is a deep dive about how to reach the top of your field in any discipline. Josh was consistently one of the best chess players in his age group growing up. He discusses why he excelled at chess and the generalizable principles he learned. In his twenties Josh transitioned away from playing chess to studying Tai Chi. Josh became the world champion of Push Hands Tai Chi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lords of the Realm</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 08:48:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</guid>
      <description>Lords of the Realm by John Helyar chronicles the history of baseball through the eyes of the owners. We generally learn about the history of sports through the great players and their influence on the game. This book looks at the owners and how they shaped the game of baseball as it developed. The book is particularly focused on the labor relations between the players and the owners.
This book showed a completely different side of baseball history than I am used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creativity Inc.</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 08:32:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/creativity/</guid>
      <description>Creativity Inc was a fantastic book looking at the culture of Pixar. It explained the founding of Pixar and how the founders maintain an intense focus on developing a fantastic culture. The founders believe that if they maintain a good culture, their business will thrive. A successful business is not about having a great product plan, but developing a good culture and empowering smart people.
I appreciated that the book did not prescribe easy solutions but discussed everything with nuance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Omnivore&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</guid>
      <description>The Omnivore&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma by Michael Pollan was an absolutely fascinating read. I enjoyed learning more about our food insutry and how the human food chain has developed. The central question of the book was where does our food come from? What seems like such a simple question has become quite complex in our modern society. I learned a lot by watching Michael try to answer this question.
  While this book dealt explicitly with our food chain, it raises a lot of questions about the complexity of our society today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>