<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 09:50:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Color of Law: A Forgotten History of How Our Government Segregated America</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/color_of_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 09:50:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/color_of_law/</guid>
      <description>The Color of Law By Richard Rothstein provides an extensive history of discrimination in housing policy in the United States. Rothstein chronicles discrimination at all levels of government and in all facets of housing. Whether it is discrimination through zoning, mortgages or schools, different levels of government continued to find new ways to enforce segregation. Rothstein refutes that housing segregation is a result of people&amp;rsquo;s preferences. He shows that housing segregation is a direct result of governmental policies that still impact our country today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter and Tear Gas: The Power and Fragility of Networked Protest </title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 16:31:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</guid>
      <description>Twitter and Tear Gas By Zeynep Tufekci is a pointedly insightful read. I had been planning to read it ever since she was interviewed on Stratechery. It felt like a really good time to read this book with the BLM protests going on across the world. Twitter and Tear Gas is part a history of modern protests, part a personal reflection and part a deep dive on the societal impacts of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Ahead in the Rain: Notes to A Tribe Called Quest</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/go_in_rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 11:02:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/go_in_rain/</guid>
      <description>Go Ahead in the Rain: Notes to a Tribe Called Quest is a beautiful book. It blends a memoir, with a history of a rap group, with a history of a time period. While the book is ostensibly about the rap group, it actualls talks about so much more than one rap group. Abdurraqib writes a poetic style of prose that conveys so much emotion.
Abdurraqib writes through the lense of his personal experience with the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Water Dancer</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/coates_water_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:15:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/coates_water_dancer/</guid>
      <description>I have read a book by Ta-Nehisi Coates each of the past two years. I read Between the World and Me two years ago and We Were Eight Years In Power last year. Both books demonstrated Coates impressive ability to forcefully convey powerful ideas. Coates is a masterful essayist. I listened to him and his editor Chris Jackson discuss The Water Dancer on the podcast Longform. I was quite excited to read Coates first novel and see how his writing style translated to a completely different medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Spring</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/silent_spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 08:53:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/silent_spring/</guid>
      <description>Silent Spring is the environmentalist Rachel Carson&amp;rsquo;s classic piece covering the dangers of pesticides. Carson explores the dangers of pesticides from so many different angles building up an intense amount of evidence of the dangers of pesticides. She highlights how harmful pesticides are to many different parts of our planet. The book is nothing if not repetitive show casing over and over again how we are doing damage to the planet with pesticides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Their Eyes Were Watching God</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 09:03:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</guid>
      <description>There Eyes Were Watching God is a novel about Janie, an African American Women born shortly after the end of slavery. The novel follows her she moves through three different husbands and living situations. This book is the most well known piece of literature by Zora Neale Hurston. The book is often read in English classes in either high school or college. I never read There Eyes Were Watching God in school; I was in the other 10th grade english class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lords of the Realm</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 08:48:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</guid>
      <description>Lords of the Realm by John Helyar chronicles the history of baseball through the eyes of the owners. We generally learn about the history of sports through the great players and their influence on the game. This book looks at the owners and how they shaped the game of baseball as it developed. The book is particularly focused on the labor relations between the players and the owners.
This book showed a completely different side of baseball history than I am used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington Black</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</guid>
      <description>Washington Black by Esi Edugyan was quite an enjoyable piece of historical fiction. Here are a couple of different themes that personally stuck out to me.
Science as an equalizer The book played around a couple of different times with the idea that science and viewing the world through a scientific lens is an equalizer. That if you viewed the world through a scientific lens then you would not discriminate against certain people and you would be better able to see the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>