<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Textbooks on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/textbooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Textbooks on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 11:59:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/textbooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Difficulty in the Concept of Social Welfare</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/difficulty_welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 11:59:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/difficulty_welfare/</guid>
      <description>I had waited to read this classic paper By Kenneth Arrow for a long time now. Since I started working in the political sphere I have been interested in how to best represents people&amp;rsquo;s opinions and how to aggregate them. This paper is so impressive because it works directly from first principles and makes all of its assumptions quite clear.
Arrow begins by asserting there are two methods by which social choices can be made in a democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mostly Harmless Econometrics Chapter 3.1</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/harmless_econ/chapter3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 11:58:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/harmless_econ/chapter3-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mostly Harmless Econometrics: Chapters 1 &amp; 2 </title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/harmless_econ/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/harmless_econ/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>Four Frequently Asked Questions The authors begin the book by discussing how to formulate research questions. The explain the path to a research questions if by asking four questions.
  What is the casual relationship of interest?
 This is not to say you cannot have purely descriptive research but purely descriptive research is a step towards causal research Causal research lets us answer questions about counterfactual worlds. A World in which something different has happened Casual questions can be asked about any unit of observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Chapters 4, 5 and 6</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_4_5_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:19:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_4_5_6/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to combine my notes from chapters four, five, and six into one post. These chapters are light on new information and heavier on examples and applications. The power of this book is the number of examples it provides. One way to learn is to look at examples and then adopt them for your own use case. This book is perfect for that type of learning.
Chapter 4 Chapter four is centered on the law of large numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 13:19:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_3/</guid>
      <description>Notes Chapter 3 in Bayesian Method for Hackers is center on Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC). It is possible to use pymc3 and bayesian models without understanding the underlying algorithms. Understanding this algorithms plays a pivotal role though if we want to be serious practitioners. When our model works out perfectly, not knowing the underlying algorithms is fine. But if we are trying to do anything complicated, our first attempt will almost certainly not work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 16:38:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_2/</guid>
      <description>Notes The chapter explains the syntax of pymc3 and how to turn different concepts into pymc3 code. It outlines the difference between a stochastic variable and determinstic variable
 A stochastic variable is random. This means even if all the information about the variable is known, we do not know what its value is. Drawing a value from a distribution is a stochastic variable. A deterministic variable can be determined from its parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Distributions</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/prob_distr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 18:32:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/prob_distr/</guid>
      <description>Discrete Distributions A discrete distribution on has specified values, such as integers. It has a probability mass function.
Poisson The poisson distribution expresses the probability that a given number of events occur in a time interval. The larger the lambda the more times the event will occur.
$$P(Z=k) = \frac{\lambda^k e^{-\lambda}}{k!}$$
$$ E[Z| \lambda] = \lambda $$
The poisson distribution provides a probability for any positive integer.
A larger lambda gives more to higher values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Methods for Hackers: Prologue and Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 18:08:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/textbooks/bayes_hackers/bayes_hackers_1/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Methods for Hackers is an online textbook created by Cam Davidson Pilon. The book focuses on bridging the gap from theory to practice. The author argues that textbooks often focus on theory to the point where they become inaccessible. By focusing on accessability these methods become avaliable to anyone.
Notes The first chapter begins with an outline of how to think in a bayesian frameworks. Bayesian methods are our process of updating beliefs after seeing new evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>