<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 15:58:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/climate_change_odsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 15:58:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/climate_change_odsc/</guid>
      <description>Talk given by David Rolnick University of Pennsylvania and founder of Climate Change AI
Motivation Climate change as an important issues does not need that much motivation. We have all seen what has been happening California recently with the wild fires. There has been increasingly severe impacts from human influence on our climate system.
One thing that is important to recognize about climate change is that different parts of the world are impacted differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Blend of Machine Learning and Microeconomics</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/ml_microecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 09:51:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/ml_microecon/</guid>
      <description>Talk given by Michael I Jordan
What is Machine Learning? The talk started by Professor Jordan defining what Machine Learning is. He said that machine learning is not some new field of research but it is rather the engineering extension of statistics. He calls back to how there was chemistry for a long time before there was chemical engineering. There was physics and electrical theory before there was electrical engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you Solve for Biased Data?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/biased_data_hawk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 16:44:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/biased_data_hawk/</guid>
      <description>My friend Hawkins recently sent me the following question:
 How do you work around biased data sets to produce non discriminatory results in ML?
 I ended up writing him a fair amount while I wan on a plane. My response to him is replicated here in full.
Hey Hawk,
Thanks for asking this question. It is a really important one and it is always nice to think about these problems in a fair amount of depth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green AI</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/green-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 03:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/green-ai/</guid>
      <description>By Roy Schwartz, Jesse Dodge, Noah A. Smith, Oren Etzioni
Summary The authors of this post argue that a large percentage of machine learning research focuses on Red AI and make a call for more research to be centered on Green AI. The authors define Red AI and Green AI as follows:  Red AI: research that makes small improvements on the state of the art by leveraging more computation resources Green AI: research that focuses on diminishing the amount of computation necessary to reach a result.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>