<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 08:53:56 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sing Unburied Sing</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/sing_unburied/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 08:53:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/sing_unburied/</guid>
      <description>Sing, Unburied Sing is a novel by Jesmyn Ward set in the American South. As with Ward&amp;rsquo;s other books, the novel does such an incredible job of getting inside characters heads. Ward is able to convey characters as nuanced individuals. She shows the darkest parts of our internal minds, how complex and convoluted they can be.
Sing, Unburied Sing feels like it is building towards something for the first half of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Marriage</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 15:25:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/am/</guid>
      <description>American Marriage by Tayari Jones is an absolutely gripping novel about a couple where the husband goes to jail for a crime he did not commit. The novel is written from the perspective of three different characters in long form first person monologues. I have not read a book in a while that was as gripping as American Marriage. There is something so powerful about first person internal monologues. The book is paced in a way that things are constantly turning and changing in different directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Their Eyes Were Watching God</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 09:03:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</guid>
      <description>There Eyes Were Watching God is a novel about Janie, an African American Women born shortly after the end of slavery. The novel follows her she moves through three different husbands and living situations. This book is the most well known piece of literature by Zora Neale Hurston. The book is often read in English classes in either high school or college. I never read There Eyes Were Watching God in school; I was in the other 10th grade english class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year of Rest and Relaxation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/r-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 17:14:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/r-r/</guid>
      <description>My Year of Rest and Relaxation by Otessa Moshfegh is quite a trip. The reader is taken inside the mind of a young adult living in New York who is trying to sleep for a entire year. The main character&amp;rsquo;s parents died and she recently left her job. She is using medication to sleep as much as possible. She hopes that after a year of sleeping she will be able to have a new start and be divorced from the darkness of her previous life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington Black</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</guid>
      <description>Washington Black by Esi Edugyan was quite an enjoyable piece of historical fiction. Here are a couple of different themes that personally stuck out to me.
Science as an equalizer The book played around a couple of different times with the idea that science and viewing the world through a scientific lens is an equalizer. That if you viewed the world through a scientific lens then you would not discriminate against certain people and you would be better able to see the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>