<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Race on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/race/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Race on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:58:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/race/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Men We Reaped: A Memoir</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/men_we_reaped/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:58:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/men_we_reaped/</guid>
      <description>Men We Reaped By Jesmyn Ward is an incredibly powerful and moving book. Ward tells a story of growing up in Mississippi and the impact it had on her community. The story looks specifically at the death of five men who were quite close to her. She tells the story from both sides. She has chapters that start at the present and work there ways backwards and chapters that start at her birth and work forwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decolonial AI: Decolonial Theory as Sociotechnical Foresight in Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/decolonial_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 12:45:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/decolonial_ai/</guid>
      <description>By Shakir Mohamed, Marie-Therese Png, and William Isaac
Paper Link
Paper Motivation Artificial Intelligence has the potential to re-shape our society. These changes could be broadly beneficial but aslo have the potential to be dangerous for vulnerable peoples. To understand the impacts of AI we need to think about values and power. It is the responsibility of the AI community to have ethical foresight and involve many different perspectives.
Paper Contribution The paper explores using post-colonial and decolonial theories to understand advances in AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing to Add: A Challenge to White Silence in Racial Discussions</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/white_silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 17:40:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2020/white_silence/</guid>
      <description>By Robin DiAngelo
The paper explores why white people are silent when talking about race. It argues that this silence, &amp;ldquo;White Silence&amp;rdquo; functions to maintain white power and privilege. The goal of the paper is to unsettle the complacency that often surrounds White Silence. TO motivate silent whites to stop being silent.
Whiteness is dynamic, relational and operating at all times and on myriad levels. It is not something simple and not easy to wrap our heads around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Color of Law: A Forgotten History of How Our Government Segregated America</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/color_of_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 09:50:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/color_of_law/</guid>
      <description>The Color of Law By Richard Rothstein provides an extensive history of discrimination in housing policy in the United States. Rothstein chronicles discrimination at all levels of government and in all facets of housing. Whether it is discrimination through zoning, mortgages or schools, different levels of government continued to find new ways to enforce segregation. Rothstein refutes that housing segregation is a result of people&amp;rsquo;s preferences. He shows that housing segregation is a direct result of governmental policies that still impact our country today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidents Happen: Exposing Fallacies in Child Protection Abuse Cases and Reuniting Families Through Aggressive Litigation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2019/accidents-happen-exposing-fallacies-in-child-protection-abuse-cases-and-reuniting-families-through-aggressive-litigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/papers/2019/accidents-happen-exposing-fallacies-in-child-protection-abuse-cases-and-reuniting-families-through-aggressive-litigation/</guid>
      <description>By Jessica Horan-Block &amp;amp; Elizabeth Tuttle Newman
Summary This paper by two attorneys at Bronx Defenders argues that quick, decisive, and aggressive action can return children to parents after abuse allegations much faster than traditional approaches. The authors outline how minority and low income parents are more frequently accused of abuse. Parents will bring their children to the Emergency Room in response to accidental injuries or strange physical developments. When the parents explanation for how the injury occurred is not deemed sufficient by the physician, they will be accused of abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
