<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington Black</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/washington_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/washington_black/</guid>
      <description>Science as an equilizer - but is it really - doest titch see washington any differently - titch as a character and actually just using washington
Trauma that stays with us - how do we deal with trauma over time - it will always be a part of us - but how do we get to a point where it does not take over us - in this bookj he feels like he has to go find titch - how can you work through these things on your own vs the importance of having others</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Omnivore&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/omnivore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/omnivore/</guid>
      <description>The Omnivore&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma by Michael Pollan was an absolutely fascinating read. I enjoyed learning more about our food insutry and how the human food chain has developed. The central question of the book was where does our food come from? What seems like such a simple question has become quite complex in our modern society. I learned a lot by watching Michael try to answer this question.
 While this book dealt explicitly with out food chain, it raises a lot of question in general about the complexity of our society today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wizard from Earthsea</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/wizard_from_earth_sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/wizard_from_earth_sea/</guid>
      <description>I read this book because of a recommendation from my friend Hawkins. I had previously read a couple of other books by Ursula Le Guin. I absolutely loved both Left Hand of Darkness and The Dispossessed. Both were sci-fi books that were actually commentaries on human society. I cannot get enough of books like that. Hawk had mentioned that this book was about a communist society and what that would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year in Review: The Books I Read in 2018</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/a-year-in-review-the-books-i-read-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 21:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/a-year-in-review-the-books-i-read-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is that time of year again when every website is publishing some piece of content trying to sum up 2018. Whether it is Facebook, posting a video that is your year in review, or a march madness style bracket to determine what person, place, or thing won 2018, everybody is attempting to summarize the past year.
A lot has happened over the past year. In 2018, I graduated college and started my first full time job.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>