<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:29:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Earth We&#39;re Briefly Gorgeous</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/briefly_gorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:29:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/briefly_gorg/</guid>
      <description>On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous By Ocean Vuong is a novel from the perspective of a narrator writing to his mother. The narrator recounts many different stories from his childhood and his relationship with different influences in his life. The letter jumps all over the place recounting stories about his Grandma&amp;rsquo;s life, to segments from the narrators point of view now that he is an adult.
This book reminded me in a lot of ways of some passages in Severance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Color of Law: A Forgotten History of How Our Government Segregated America</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/color_of_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 09:50:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/color_of_law/</guid>
      <description>The Color of Law By Richard Rothstein provides an extensive history of discrimination in housing policy in the United States. Rothstein chronicles discrimination at all levels of government and in all facets of housing. Whether it is discrimination through zoning, mortgages or schools, different levels of government continued to find new ways to enforce segregation. Rothstein refutes that housing segregation is a result of people&amp;rsquo;s preferences. He shows that housing segregation is a direct result of governmental policies that still impact our country today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl, Woman, Other</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/girl_woman_other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 10:54:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/girl_woman_other/</guid>
      <description>Girl, Woman, Other by Bernardine Evaristo is a mix of a novel with a set of short stories. Each chapter is told from the perspective of a different women in England. Some of the stories are set in the present and some of them are set a hundred years ago. The stories cover a vast range of different experiences from people who grew up very poor to people who grew up with some wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter and Tear Gas: The Power and Fragility of Networked Protest </title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 16:31:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/twitter_and_tear_gas/</guid>
      <description>Twitter and Tear Gas By Zeynep Tufekci is a pointedly insightful read. I had been planning to read it ever since she was interviewed on Stratechery. It felt like a really good time to read this book with the BLM protests going on across the world. Twitter and Tear Gas is part a history of modern protests, part a personal reflection and part a deep dive on the societal impacts of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking the Electorate: How Campaigns Percieve Voters</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hacking_electorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 13:35:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hacking_electorate/</guid>
      <description>Hacking the Electorate By Eitan Hersh is an depth look at what information is accessible to campaigns and how they use that information to interact with voters. Hersh contextualizes his work by highlighting that he is focusing on the perspective of a campaign. A lot of previous research is through the lense perspective of voters. Hersh&amp;rsquo;s main argument is that by looking through the perspective of campaigns we can understand how campaigns perceive voters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exhalation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/exhalation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 13:35:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/exhalation/</guid>
      <description>Exhalation by Ted Chiang is a set of short stories that really showcases some of what I love about sci-fi. Chiang uses each story to explore our contemporary culture in a way that is only possible through sci-fi. Good science fiction is not writing about a different. It is writing about our own society and using other places to provide a context that would not be possible otherwise. By looking at and asking questions about what the world would look like in other scenarios we can better understand our own world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperion</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hyperion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 13:13:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hyperion/</guid>
      <description>Hyperion by Dan Simmons is likely to join the group of sci-fi series where I read the first novel in the series and then do not read the others. This in no way means that I did not enjoy the book, but I find the first book in sci-fi series to be the most compelling. The world building and the introduction of characters is so gripping. There are so many books out there that I am compelled to read and so I often do not continue with the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trick Mirror: Reflections on Self Delusion</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/trick_mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/trick_mirror/</guid>
      <description>Trick Mirror by Jia Tolentino is a series of essays exploring identity and the self in our current era. Tolentino blends personal stories and self reflections with larger dissections of structural systems in our society. I found Tolentino&amp;rsquo;s writing incredibly compelling. She does not prescribe absolutes and allows nuance to shine through. She does not prescribe exact solutions but rather examines structures in our society and how she navigates them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations with Friends</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/conv_friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 14:15:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/conv_friends/</guid>
      <description>Conversations with Friends is the second book in the past month that I have read by Sally Rooney. Similarly to Normal People, this novel explores communication between people in romantic relationships. It highlights the dangers and destructive nature of expecting others to understand us. When we expect others to understand rather than communicating there will be failures. We make assumptions about how other people are processing events and get caught in the world inside our heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Ahead in the Rain: Notes to A Tribe Called Quest</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/go_in_rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 11:02:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/go_in_rain/</guid>
      <description>Go Ahead in the Rain: Notes to a Tribe Called Quest is a beautiful book. It blends a memoir, with a history of a rap group, with a history of a time period. While the book is ostensibly about the rap group, it actualls talks about so much more than one rap group. Abdurraqib writes a poetic style of prose that conveys so much emotion.
Abdurraqib writes through the lense of his personal experience with the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severance</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/severance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 10:28:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/severance/</guid>
      <description>Severance by Ling Ma is easily one of my favorite books of the year. Severance elegantly ties together many different genres. It is an immigrant story, a coming of age story, a story about heritage and an apocalypse story. Ma blends these different stories into one cohesive narrative. Often during apocalypse novels the majority of the focus is on surviving and how the world has changed. Tieing the apocalypse to an individual&amp;rsquo;s history allowed us to explore how Candace&amp;rsquo;s past impacted her actions during the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch and Kill</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/catch_kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:36:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/catch_kill/</guid>
      <description>Reading Catch and Kill by Ronan Farrow was a real eye opener for me. I knew who Harvey Weinstein was but I did not know any of the details. A lot of the events covered in the book happened while I was in college when I did not really follow the news.
My largest takeaway was that while the book might be centered on Harvey Weinstein, it is actually about so much more than any individual man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normal People</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/normal_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 16:57:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/normal_people/</guid>
      <description>Normal People by Sally Rooney is one of my most anticipated books in the past couple of years. I had heard from many different sources about how good this book is. Family, friends and numerous co-workers all recommended it highly. It is relatively rare that I hear praise about a book from so many different sources.
I can see why so many different people enjoyed Rooney&amp;rsquo;s writing. She does an incredible job portraying emotion and what it feels like to be in your late teens / early twenties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Will You Measure Your Life?</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/cc_ja_how_measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:10:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/cc_ja_how_measure/</guid>
      <description>I was introduced to this book through Stratechery and Exponent. One of the co-hosts of Exponent, James Allworth, is a co-author of this book. While I have been reading Ben Thompson&amp;rsquo;s (the author of Stratechery) writing for a couple years now, I knew a lot less about Allworth and his background. While James is a co-author of this book, the book is written from the perspective of Clayton Christensen. Christensen a professor at Harvard Business School, is best known for his work The Innovator&amp;rsquo;s Dillema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Water Dancer</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/coates_water_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:15:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/coates_water_dancer/</guid>
      <description>I have read a book by Ta-Nehisi Coates each of the past two years. I read Between the World and Me two years ago and We Were Eight Years In Power last year. Both books demonstrated Coates impressive ability to forcefully convey powerful ideas. Coates is a masterful essayist. I listened to him and his editor Chris Jackson discuss The Water Dancer on the podcast Longform. I was quite excited to read Coates first novel and see how his writing style translated to a completely different medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Economics for Hard Times</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/economics_bad_times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 08:40:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/economics_bad_times/</guid>
      <description>I have read a lot of &amp;ldquo;pop&amp;rdquo; science books and Good Economics for Hard Times is easily the best. Duflo and Banerjee explore very complex topics with nuance. They do an incredible job of conveying where there is uncertainty and what we know more definitively. Duflo and Banerjee both review the existing literature and expand upon potential future directions. Good Economics for Hard Times provides structure for thinking about complex problems like immigration or automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/zen_mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 08:52:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/zen_mm/</guid>
      <description>Before reading Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance I had no knowledge about what genre the book was or what it would be about. I actually potentially had some misconceptions about the content of the book. While I reading it, I actually thought it was a piece of fiction. Only when I read the afterword did I learn that it was actually semi auto-biographical. My friend Abhisaar recommended this book and I finally got around to it after about two years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braiding Sweet Grass</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/braiding_sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/braiding_sg/</guid>
      <description>Braiding Sweet Grass is a set of short stories about nature from Robin Kimmerer&amp;rsquo;s life. Kimmerer blends a scientific perspective with a perspective from from her heritage as a Native American. While each story is about an individual relationship between humans and nature, she often makes larger points about how human view themselves in the world. Kimmerer questions human&amp;rsquo;s claim of intelligent supremacy, challenges some of our economic systems and laments different ways our society is narrow minded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sing Unburied Sing</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/sing_unburied/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 08:53:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/sing_unburied/</guid>
      <description>Sing, Unburied Sing is a novel by Jesmyn Ward set in the American South. As with Ward&amp;rsquo;s other books, the novel does such an incredible job of getting inside characters heads. Ward is able to convey characters as nuanced individuals. She shows the darkest parts of our internal minds, how complex and convoluted they can be.
Sing, Unburied Sing feels like it is building towards something for the first half of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Spring</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/silent_spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 08:53:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/silent_spring/</guid>
      <description>Silent Spring is the environmentalist Rachel Carson&amp;rsquo;s classic piece covering the dangers of pesticides. Carson explores the dangers of pesticides from so many different angles building up an intense amount of evidence of the dangers of pesticides. She highlights how harmful pesticides are to many different parts of our planet. The book is nothing if not repetitive show casing over and over again how we are doing damage to the planet with pesticides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Marriage</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 15:25:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/am/</guid>
      <description>American Marriage by Tayari Jones is an absolutely gripping novel about a couple where the husband goes to jail for a crime he did not commit. The novel is written from the perspective of three different characters in long form first person monologues. I have not read a book in a while that was as gripping as American Marriage. There is something so powerful about first person internal monologues. The book is paced in a way that things are constantly turning and changing in different directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Learning</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/a_of_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 08:00:18 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/a_of_learning/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Learning by Josh Waitzkin is a deep dive about how to reach the top of your field in any discipline. Josh was consistently one of the best chess players in his age group growing up. He discusses why he excelled at chess and the generalizable principles he learned. In his twenties Josh transitioned away from playing chess to studying Tai Chi. Josh became the world champion of Push Hands Tai Chi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 in Review: The Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/year_review_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 09:49:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/year_review_2019/</guid>
      <description>As another year passes I reflect on what I did over the past year and what I learned. Looking back it is tempting to focus on what has changed over the past year. It is tempting to compare where I am now and where I was a year ago. I have moved to a new city and started a new job. But comparing one year to another is so divorced from the actual experience of a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Their Eyes Were Watching God</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 09:03:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</guid>
      <description>There Eyes Were Watching God is a novel about Janie, an African American Women born shortly after the end of slavery. The novel follows her she moves through three different husbands and living situations. This book is the most well known piece of literature by Zora Neale Hurston. The book is often read in English classes in either high school or college. I never read There Eyes Were Watching God in school; I was in the other 10th grade english class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lords of the Realm</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 08:48:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</guid>
      <description>Lords of the Realm by John Helyar chronicles the history of baseball through the eyes of the owners. We generally learn about the history of sports through the great players and their influence on the game. This book looks at the owners and how they shaped the game of baseball as it developed. The book is particularly focused on the labor relations between the players and the owners.
This book showed a completely different side of baseball history than I am used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year of Rest and Relaxation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/r-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 17:14:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/r-r/</guid>
      <description>My Year of Rest and Relaxation by Otessa Moshfegh is quite a trip. The reader is taken inside the mind of a young adult living in New York who is trying to sleep for a entire year. The main character&amp;rsquo;s parents died and she recently left her job. She is using medication to sleep as much as possible. She hopes that after a year of sleeping she will be able to have a new start and be divorced from the darkness of her previous life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creativity Inc.</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 08:32:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/creativity/</guid>
      <description>Creativity Inc was a fantastic book looking at the culture of Pixar. It explained the founding of Pixar and how the founders maintain an intense focus on developing a fantastic culture. The founders believe that if they maintain a good culture, their business will thrive. A successful business is not about having a great product plan, but developing a good culture and empowering smart people.
I appreciated that the book did not prescribe easy solutions but discussed everything with nuance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington Black</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</guid>
      <description>Washington Black by Esi Edugyan was quite an enjoyable piece of historical fiction. Here are a couple of different themes that personally stuck out to me.
Science as an equalizer The book played around a couple of different times with the idea that science and viewing the world through a scientific lens is an equalizer. That if you viewed the world through a scientific lens then you would not discriminate against certain people and you would be better able to see the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Omnivore&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</guid>
      <description>The Omnivore&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma by Michael Pollan was an absolutely fascinating read. I enjoyed learning more about our food insutry and how the human food chain has developed. The central question of the book was where does our food come from? What seems like such a simple question has become quite complex in our modern society. I learned a lot by watching Michael try to answer this question.
 While this book dealt explicitly with our food chain, it raises a lot of questions about the complexity of our society today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wizard from Earthsea</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/wizard_from_earth_sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/wizard_from_earth_sea/</guid>
      <description>I read this book because of a recommendation from my friend Hawkins. I had previously read a couple of other books by Ursula Le Guin. I absolutely loved both Left Hand of Darkness and The Dispossessed. Both were sci-fi books that were actually commentaries on human society. I cannot get enough of books like that. Hawk had mentioned that this book was about a communist society and what that would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year in Review: The Books I Read in 2018</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/a-year-in-review-the-books-i-read-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 21:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/a-year-in-review-the-books-i-read-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is that time of year again when every website is publishing some piece of content trying to sum up 2018. Whether it is Facebook, posting a video that is your year in review, or a march madness style bracket to determine what person, place, or thing won 2018, everybody is attempting to summarize the past year.
A lot has happened over the past year. In 2018, I graduated college and started my first full time job.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>