<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 09:49:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 in Review: The Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/year_review_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 09:49:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/year_review_2019/</guid>
      <description>As another year passes I reflect on what I did over the past year and what I learned. Looking back it is tempting to focus on what has changed over the past year. It is tempting to compare where I am now and where I was a year ago. I have moved to a new city and started a new job. But comparing one year to another is so divorced from the actual experience of a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Their Eyes Were Watching God</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 09:03:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/their_eyes/</guid>
      <description>There Eyes Were Watching God is a novel about Janie, an African American Women born shortly after the end of slavery. The novel follows her she moves through three different husbands and living situations. This book is the most well known piece of literature by Zora Neale Hurston. The book is often read in English classes in either high school or college. I never read There Eyes Were Watching God in school; I was in the other 10th grade english class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lords of the Realm</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 08:48:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/lords/</guid>
      <description>Lords of the Realm by John Helyar chronicles the history of baseball through the eyes of the owners. We generally learn about the history of sports through the great players and their influence on the game. This book looks at the owners and how they shaped the game of baseball as it developed. The book is particularly focused on the labor relations between the players and the owners.
This book showed a completely different side of baseball history than I am used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year of Rest and Relaxation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/r-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 17:14:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/r-r/</guid>
      <description>My Year of Rest and Relaxation by Otessa Moshfegh is quite a trip. The reader is taken inside the mind of a young adult living in New York who is trying to sleep for a entire year. The main character&amp;rsquo;s parents died and she recently left her job. She is using medication to sleep as much as possible. She hopes that after a year of sleeping she will be able to have a new start and be divorced from the darkness of her previous life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creativity Inc.</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 08:32:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/creativity/</guid>
      <description>Creativity Inc was a fantastic book looking at the culture of Pixar. It explained the founding of Pixar and how the founders maintain an intense focus on developing a fantastic culture. The founders believe that if they maintain a good culture, their business will thrive. A successful business is not about having a great product plan, but developing a good culture and empowering smart people.
I appreciated that the book did not prescribe easy solutions but discussed everything with nuance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington Black</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/washington_black/</guid>
      <description>Washington Black by Esi Edugyan was quite an enjoyable piece of historical fiction. Here are a couple of different themes that personally stuck out to me.
Science as an equalizer The book played around a couple of different times with the idea that science and viewing the world through a scientific lens is an equalizer. That if you viewed the world through a scientific lens then you would not discriminate against certain people and you would be better able to see the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Omnivore&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</guid>
      <description>The Omnivore&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma by Michael Pollan was an absolutely fascinating read. I enjoyed learning more about our food insutry and how the human food chain has developed. The central question of the book was where does our food come from? What seems like such a simple question has become quite complex in our modern society. I learned a lot by watching Michael try to answer this question.
 While this book dealt explicitly with our food chain, it raises a lot of questions about the complexity of our society today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wizard from Earthsea</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/wizard_from_earth_sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/wizard_from_earth_sea/</guid>
      <description>I read this book because of a recommendation from my friend Hawkins. I had previously read a couple of other books by Ursula Le Guin. I absolutely loved both Left Hand of Darkness and The Dispossessed. Both were sci-fi books that were actually commentaries on human society. I cannot get enough of books like that. Hawk had mentioned that this book was about a communist society and what that would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year in Review: The Books I Read in 2018</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/a-year-in-review-the-books-i-read-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 21:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/a-year-in-review-the-books-i-read-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is that time of year again when every website is publishing some piece of content trying to sum up 2018. Whether it is Facebook, posting a video that is your year in review, or a march madness style bracket to determine what person, place, or thing won 2018, everybody is attempting to summarize the past year.
A lot has happened over the past year. In 2018, I graduated college and started my first full time job.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>