<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nature on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 14:47:18 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Braiding Sweet Grass</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/braiding_sg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 14:47:18 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/braiding_sg/</guid>
      <description>Braiding Sweet Grass is a set of short stories about nature from Robin Kimmerer&amp;rsquo;s life. Kimmerer blends a scientific perspective with a perspective from from her heritage as a Native American. While each story is about an individual relationship between humans and nature, she often makes larger points about how human view themselves in the world. Kimmerer questions human&amp;rsquo;s claim of intelligent supremacy, challenges some of our economic systems and laments different ways our society is narrow minded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Spring</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/silent_spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 08:53:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/silent_spring/</guid>
      <description>Silent Spring is the environmentalist Rachel Carson&amp;rsquo;s classic piece covering the dangers of pesticides. Carson explores the dangers of pesticides from so many different angles building up an intense amount of evidence of the dangers of pesticides. She highlights how harmful pesticides are to many different parts of our planet. The book is nothing if not repetitive show casing over and over again how we are doing damage to the planet with pesticides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Omnivore&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/omnivore/</guid>
      <description>The Omnivore&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma by Michael Pollan was an absolutely fascinating read. I enjoyed learning more about our food insutry and how the human food chain has developed. The central question of the book was where does our food come from? What seems like such a simple question has become quite complex in our modern society. I learned a lot by watching Michael try to answer this question.
 While this book dealt explicitly with our food chain, it raises a lot of questions about the complexity of our society today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/talks/odsc/climate_change_odsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 15:58:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/talks/odsc/climate_change_odsc/</guid>
      <description>Talk given by David Rolnick University of Pennsylvania and founder of Climate Change AI
Motivation Climate change as an important issues does not need that much motivation. We have all seen what has been happening California recently with the wild fires. There has been increasingly severe impacts from human influence on our climate system.
One thing that is important to recognize about climate change is that different parts of the world are impacted differently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>