<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/science-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 16:04:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/tags/science-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Girl and Other Stories</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hidden_girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 16:04:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hidden_girl/</guid>
      <description>The Hidden Girl and Other Stories by Ken Liu us a book of short science fiction stories. There is one set of stories that is a trilogy but otherwise each story is a standalone.
There were a lot of stories in this collection and I found most of them to be a little underwhelming. There was one story though that I thought was very powerful. The story was about charitable giving and how we think about our own impacts on the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Memory Police</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/memory_police/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 16:01:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/memory_police/</guid>
      <description>The Memory Police By Yoko Ogawa is a very slow paced unnerving science-fiction novel. The novel takes place on an island where objects are slowly disappearing from people&amp;rsquo;s memory. One day everyone wakes up and they no longer have the memory about a certain object. They proceed to destroy all instances of that object. This forgetfulness does not impact everyone on the island though. There are some people who do not forget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/ted_chiang_story_of_your_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:55:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/ted_chiang_story_of_your_life/</guid>
      <description>Stories of Your Life and Others is a book of science fiction short stories by Ted Chiang. Chiang is one of my favorite writers. I love the way he brings real science into his science fiction. He is not writing about completely fictional worlds. He uses science fiction to force us to think about our own world and our own science in a different way.
This book is for sure weaker than his other book of short stories Exhalation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exhalation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/exhalation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 13:35:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/exhalation/</guid>
      <description>Exhalation by Ted Chiang is a set of short stories that really showcases some of what I love about sci-fi. Chiang uses each story to explore our contemporary culture in a way that is only possible through sci-fi. Good science fiction is not writing about a different. It is writing about our own society and using other places to provide a context that would not be possible otherwise. By looking at and asking questions about what the world would look like in other scenarios we can better understand our own world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperion</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hyperion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 13:13:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/hyperion/</guid>
      <description>Hyperion by Dan Simmons is likely to join the group of sci-fi series where I read the first novel in the series and then do not read the others. This in no way means that I did not enjoy the book, but I find the first book in sci-fi series to be the most compelling. The world building and the introduction of characters is so gripping. There are so many books out there that I am compelled to read and so I often do not continue with the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severance</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/severance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 10:28:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2020/severance/</guid>
      <description>Severance by Ling Ma is easily one of my favorite books of the year. Severance elegantly ties together many different genres. It is an immigrant story, a coming of age story, a story about heritage and an apocalypse story. Ma blends these different stories into one cohesive narrative. Often during apocalypse novels the majority of the focus is on surviving and how the world has changed. Tieing the apocalypse to an individual&amp;rsquo;s history allowed us to explore how Candace&amp;rsquo;s past impacted her actions during the apocalypse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wizard from Earthsea</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/wizard_from_earth_sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 08:02:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/books/2019/wizard_from_earth_sea/</guid>
      <description>I read this book because of a recommendation from my friend Hawkins. I had previously read a couple of other books by Ursula Le Guin. I absolutely loved both Left Hand of Darkness and The Dispossessed. Both were sci-fi books that were actually commentaries on human society. I cannot get enough of books like that. Hawk had mentioned that this book was about a communist society and what that would look like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>