<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Industry on Welcome</title>
    <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Industry on Welcome</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:18:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/categories/industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Models and the Scientific Method</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/model_building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:18:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/personal/model_building/</guid>
      <description>In the past year there has been a large focus on what is wrong with the fields of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. Coverage has focused on limitations of current deep learning and machine learning systems. Pieces have highlighted the dangers of implementing systems without understanding their implications or who they are going to impact. These pieces have highlighted areas where these fields need to grow. Machine Learning is still a relatively young field that needs to grow and learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Nielsen</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 10:33:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/leaving/</guid>
      <description>Why I am leaving Nielsen Nielsen was my first experience working at a full time job and in a lot of ways it was a good one. I learned an immense amount and became a much better data scientist. I met a lot of very smart people who helped me grow and taught me a lot. There were a lot of frustrations though during my time at Nielsen and I thought it would be worthwhile to expand upon why I am leaving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Community of Practice: Nielsen</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/ml_cop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/ml_cop/</guid>
      <description>Project Description The Machine Learning community of practice was a one stop shop for all things machine learning at Nielsen. The goal of the organization was to provide resources related to machine learning. We recorded all of the different projects being worked on related to machine learning, who were the different machine learning experts in different fields and maintained general learning resources.
We hosted monthly webinars that highlighted different machine learning projects around the organization and provided a forum for practitioners to present their work and get feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Time At Nielsen</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/my_time_at_nielsen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/my_time_at_nielsen/</guid>
      <description>What I Did at Nielsen My first job after completing undergrad was as a Data Scientist at Nielsen. Nielsen is a market research company that provides insight about what people buy and what media content they consume. I was a part of Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s early career program focused on fast tracking individuals to leadership roles. The program consists of four six months rotations for a total of two years. During my time at Nielsen I wrote about what I worked on and what I was learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotation 1: Non-coop estimation</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/rotation_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/rotation_1/</guid>
      <description>Project Description Nielsen receives data from retailers about all of the items they sell. For example, Walmart sends Nielsen all of the products sold at each store in the past week. Brands, such as Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, use this information to see how much of their product is being bought. Some retailers do not send Nielsen their data. We will refer to these retailers as non-cooperators. Non-cooperators do not send Nielsen their data because the majority of the items they sell are from their own brand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotation 2: Bayesian Inference for Ratings</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/rotation_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/rotation_2/</guid>
      <description>Project Description Nielsen is best known for their linear television ratings which estimate the number of people who were watching a channel at any time. This information is estimated using a representative panel of households all across the United States. Households in Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s Panel report all of the television that they watch. Each household&amp;rsquo;s viewing is weight based on its demographics to ensure that the viewing is representative of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotation 3: Digital Pipeline Development</title>
      <link>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/rotation_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://judahgnewman.netlify.com/writing/industry/nielsen/rotation_3/</guid>
      <description>Project Description Nielsen is in the process of transforming how we build our products. We are a ninety five year old company that is not technologically native. We are working on building products that are more maintainable and reducing the amount of work that we duplicate. Data science in particular is undergoing a large transformation within Nielsen. Previously, Data Science sat very far away from the final product and a large portion of the data science organization did not have the technical skills to build reliable technical products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>